hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we are going to make chocolate
orange cinnamon roll ice cream or if you
don't want the ice cream bit chocolate
orange cinnamon
[Music]
rolls so yeah I made these cinnamon
rolls
or a year ago and they were
astonishingly good and in that time I've
been meaning to make an ice cream out of
it but you know one thing led to another
so what we're going to do today is make
the cinnamon rolls and and turn them
into ice cream for this recipe you're
going to need 60 G of unsalted butter
220 G of milk 11 G of fast acting yeast
if you want to use instant you know
super fast that's fine 50 g of sugar 1
medium egg at room temperature and one
egg yolk at room temperature 460 G of
strong white flour 50 g of dark cocoa
powder and 5 G of salt first thing we
need to do is to melt our 60 G of butter
and then warm up our milk to around 50
to 60°
Centigrade there's the
[Music]
butter like that into the milk we're
going to put 11
[Music]
G which is just over 2 tpoon of
our fast acting yeast and whisk that
together you whisk the milk and yeast
together just to get it hydrated cuz
we're going to leave that there for a
few minutes let's make some
room got our stand mixer with our dough
hook so what we're going to do is we're
going to put our flour into our Mixing
Bowl going to add in our sugar our salt
our cocoa powder our our one whole
egg and our one egg yolk now we have our
butter and our milk and yeast mix so
what we're going to do is get this
mixing together and add our liquids
in in goes our butter and finally our
milk and we're going to keep stirring
this until it's all combined then we're
going to mix it on a medium speed for
about 7 minutes it's not exact what
you're looking for is for the dough to
come away from the outside of the bowl
and it be nice and clean right now with
that done the I'll show you the bowl in
a minute what we're going to do is just
take
a going to put a tiny little drop of oil
it's only a
teaspoon because all we need to do
is make sure that that dough doesn't
stick to the inside of this
bowl like so
right there here is our dough as you can
see the bowl is lovely and clean the
dough Has Come Together perfectly it's
got a little bit spring to it it's
nicely
combined that's what we're looking for
all we're now going to do is to take
this out of this
bowl like
that put that in
here and we're going to leave that for
about 90 minutes to 2 hours something
like that that will double in size and
then we'll come back and get them
baking okay so we
have doubled in size
nice still got a nice shape to it it's
got good body now we need to roll this
out into something like a 14 in by 9 in
square something like that we're going
to need a bit of flour
and a rolling
pan
nice this dough doesn't want to be too
wet it kind of needs to be a reasonably
dry dough
but has spring as well I actually
started with this
dough by taking a a
known entity and then just adjusting it
to soup there is our
rectangle like
that little bit more we don't want it to
stick
now next stage going to take our soften
butter and we're going to smear that
over the
[Music]
top now with that we're going to add in
our
cinnamon and get a
fork and if you've got really sticky
brown sugar then you're just going to
combine it because we want that cinnamon
to be evenly distributed you can
sprinkle this over the top of
your your dough the cinnamon and then
put the sugar on top that is actually
fine whatever works for you this is just
the way that I learned how to make it
and you'll find that as you do this the
cinnamon powder coats the Molasses that
is in the sugar and
that makes it much less
sticky much easier to work next take a
spoon and you're going to start just
Distributing that over the
top so we have one more stage we're
going to take an orange this the only
oranges that they had in the store
they're tiny um I'm going to wash this
to make sure there's no wax on there
wash it with warm water and a sponge
just to get any coating off and we're
going to grate that over the top
[Music]
quick tidy up and now we're going to
roll this forward so we've got our thin
edges here and then our long edges here
you're rolling that way so you get a
long length of dough and what you need
to do is just grab the
ends and just pull it back cuz it
will have shrunk ever so
slightly and then tuck it as you start
to roll it like that and what I find is
just give it a slight little pull as you
roll it like this like that now what you
have is a long cylinder of dough pinch
the end
together if it doesn't want to stick
don't worry too much because we're going
to put these in a pan right
now like so take a knife and we're going
to lose the ends like that there's not a
lot going in there and we're going to
cut the these into 1 and 1/2 in kind of
size so somewhere around 35 mm once
you've cut it we're then going to place
it in our pan and now we're going to
cover
this and we're going to leave this to
rise again for another hour we're going
to do a super easy vanilla cinnamon ice
cream this is a condensed milk based one
so nice and easy to do there's enough
work going into the cinnamon buns as it
is so we don't need to make life any
harder for us as we don't need to chill
that one down we're going to do that
right at the end so with our oven up to
350 F 18c we're going to get our
cinnamon buns and put them in and get
them cooking for 18 to 20 minutes keep
an eye make sure they don't burn we
don't want that and when they're ready
and your oven beeper goes off like a
crazy person we're going to take them
out and let them cool out our cinnamon
buns have cooled enough we can now do
our frosting for the cinnamon buns get
rid of that what we have here is 50 g of
milk chocolate 50 g of icing sugar
powdered sugar 75 G of full fat cream
cheese and we're going to use the orange
juice from the one orange that we used
whilst making these so first thing we
need to do is just warm this up in the
microwave until it's malleable so until
we can work it so that was 20 seconds in
the microw wave and it's just made it
nice and soft it's not hot but it's sof
so we can actually work it into that we
are going to put our icing sugar and
work all of that together like so
doesn't take long to do that was about
30 seconds worth of stirring next we
need to melt our chocolate do this
gently short stages until it's
completely liquid as it starts to melt
that's the stage to stop because we
don't want this to burn in the microwave
so it's much better to bring it out you
know a little bit early and then you can
stir it together and any remaining
chocolate that hasn't melted will melt
with the rest pour our melted chocolate
into our cream cheese cream cheese
mixture and then combine all of that
together and finally we just need to do
our
orange so we're going to cut that in
half this is a seedless
orange and then one final mix together
and there we have a
glorious chocolate orange cream cheese
topping right quick tidy up this is the
perfect stage to freeze some cinnamon
buns if you're making a larger batch
freeze them after they've cooled but
before you've topped them but these will
keep in the freezer for months the next
thing to do is literally just dip one of
your glorious chocolate
orange cinnamon buns into your topping
like that let's do the other ones
and there we have our cinnamon buns that
we're going to use for our ice cream so
ice cream finally I hear some of you say
using condensed milk we need our scales
we're going to need 350 G worth of milk
350 G of our whipping cream 300 mL of
condensed milk 1 and 1/2 tpoon of our
vanilla bean paste some cinnamon we're
going to put about 1 half teaspoon of
cinnamon you can go a bit bit higher
with that one depending on how strong
you like your flavor but next you are
simply just going to whisk all this
together until it's completely combined
if you're using a ninja creamy for this
just pour some in your Ninja creamy tub
freeze it and then spin it as normal
keep these in the refrigerator to add
these into your ninja creamy chop them
up and add them after you've spun don't
put these in and then spin them on an
add in setting decimates everything you
want some nice chunky pieces of this in
there so if that's what you're doing
with your ninja creamy that's how to do
it I'm going to use my traditional
machine to make this because I want to
so first thing we going to do is
pre-chill our machine for a few minutes
and then get our ice cream base in there
and then we're going to chop up our
delicious chocolate orange cinnamon buns
into small kind of Cubes whatever size
suits you and load them up between
layers of ice cream there's our result
let's get some scooped up and into a
bowl because this looks delicious you've
got this super lovely texture with flex
of orange dest coming out through there
and those pieces of cinnamon bun poking
through chocolate
orange cinnamon bun ice cream obviously
if you just want a chocolate orange
cinnamon bun separate that from the ice
cream I decided to make a super easy ice
cream because this is a lot of work goes
into the cinnamon buns which are
delicious I mean really really good
we've actually eaten all of them
but you've got a really nice warming
cinnamon smell coming out of this ice
cream again super easy with that
condensed
milk texture super smooth the cinnamon
bun dough doesn't go super super hard in
the base cuz the liquid starts absorbing
into it so it's a perfect kind of
texture break to the ice cream when you
bite into into some of that cinnamon bun
you get a rush of brown sugar and orange
zest come through there after tone of
chocolate that cocoa
powder and then you've got the warming
Taste of cinnamon ice cream coming in
after that the vanilla is there to boost
the cinnamon flavor this is such a good
combo delicious I haven't done complex
makes for a while so this is step back
to the old days when I used to make lots
of things to go in the ice cream there's
another one coming up actually in in the
next week or two which is a Christmas
ice cream flavor one I've never done
before that's just for the ninja creamy
well it's not you can make it and in
whatever you like but it's a ninja cream
video thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe and I
will see you next
[Music]
time is issued by the colia